xplace.com 2019-05-28

# XPlace | Privacy Statement

XPlace Privacy Statement

Updated: July 2012. 

"Site" refers to this Internet web site and its related services. In only this Privacy Policy, "You" or "User" refers to a registered user of this Site. "XPlace" or "We" refers to XPlace, Inc. 

XPlace has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. This Privacy Agreement is hereby incorporated in our Terms and Conditions of Use and by registering for our service You accept the terms of this Privacy Agreement. 

_Notification of Changes_

We may update this Privacy Agreement from time to time as our services change and expand. If We update this Privacy Agreement, we will post the updated Agreement on this page. Unless otherwise provided below, the revised terms will take effect when they are posted. Once any changes that We make to this Privacy Agreement become effective, your continued use of the Site after such time will signify your acceptance of the new terms. 

_This Site contains links to other sites_

XPlace is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other Web sites to which the Site links or to which link to the Site. By clicking on a link, logo or other item, please note that You may no longer be on the XPlace site. To check what Internet location you are on, note the URL at the top and/or bottom of your browser. We encourage You to read the posted privacy statement of that web site whenever interacting with any web site. 

## Information We Gather

_Registration_

If You register with XPlace, We collect and store information that specifically identifies You or your account. At this time, information You are required to submit is your first name, last name, User ID, password, country, phone number, email address and an indication as to whether you would like to register as a project owner only or also as a expert. 

_Online Surveys_

Occasionally XPlace may choose to conduct online user surveys to collect information about our Users' preferences. These surveys are optional and if You choose to respond, your responses may or may not be kept anonymous. The demographic information that XPlace collects in the registration process and through online surveys is used to help us improve our services to meet the needs and preferences of our Users. This may include targeting advertising to You about our services. 

_Automatically Gathered Information_

XPlace automatically collects your browser type and browser software version to tailor the presentation of the services to your platform and to maintain a record of your activity on the Site. XPlace uses cookies to enable Users to specify unique preferences and to track user trends and patterns. Users always have the option of disabling cookies via their browser preferences. If You disable cookies on your browser, please note that some parts of our Site may not function as effectively or may be considerably slower. As an automatic process, our web server software records a log file of IP addresses that access the Site. We also collect IP address information but do not ordinarily link IP addresses to Users' personal information. However, We can and will use IP addresses to identify a User when We, in our sole discretion, determine that it is necessary to enforce compliance with our Terms and Conditions of Use or to protect our service, Site, customers or others. 

_Emails, Newsletters and Promotional Material_

By using XPlace, you agree and acknowledge that XPlace may use your information as follows: 

  * To contact you with administrative communications, email newsletters, marketing or promotional materials (on behalf of XPlace or third parties) and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, you may follow the instructions at the bottom of the email message you received, on your settings page or by emailing support [at] xplace.com;
  * To provide and improve the service, complete your transactions, and address your inquiries, process your registration, verify the information you provide is valid and for compliance and internal business purposes;
  * To tailor content we display to you and offers we may present to you, both on XPLACE and elsewhere online;
  * To administer and develop our business relationship with you and, if applicable, the company you represent;

XPLACE retains the information we collect for at least 5 years and may retain the information for as long as needed for our business and legal purposes. 

XPLACE reserves the sole right at its own discretion to unsubscribe you from receiving communications, newsletters or promotional content with or without advanced notice to you. 

_Email to Friends Feature and Referral Program_

XPlace lets both registered users and visitors easily send project postings and user profiles to friends via email. XPlace also offers the ability to send friends emails about providing or purchasing services through XPlace. If You choose to use any of these features, be assured that XPlace only uses your friends' email addresses on a one-time basis to send the requested posting and We use your email address to copy You on the message or to send on your behalf. 

_Your User Profile_

As part of registration, You may set up a User Profile describing your experience and qualifications. If You decide to act as a expert, potential project owners will look to your User Profile to help them decide whether to accept a bid from You. As a result, we suggest that You update your a User Profile with current information about yourself or your company. 

_Your Payment Information_

When making purchases of any kind on XPlace, users must enter their credit card information. This information is kept on secure servers and in encrypted databases to prevent any unauthorized access by third-parties or other unauthorized users.. Users who wish to have their credit card information purged from XPlace's secure databases, can notify XPlace by by email to support [at] XPlace.com or mail, to the address below. Please note that users who request to have their credit card information purged from XPlace's secure database may lose their subscriptions and existing status in the marketplace, which may limit their ongoing business activities, access to other members, access to projects, and may experience other adverse membership effects. XPlace will not be liable for any damages caused to user's ability to transact on XPlace or use the site as a result of the removal of a user's payment information from the Company's databases. 

## How We Use Information

_Registration Information_

We use your information for our own internal purposes including contacting You via email to inform You about updates to our services and providing You with information relating to e-commerce transactions that You conduct on the Site. We reserve the right to disclose your information as required by law. We do not rent or sell our Users' information to third parties. We do, however, provide You with the opportunity to receive newsletters via email. If You decide to opt-in to receive newsletters, You may opt out of receiving these newsletters at any time by sending a message to the unsubscribe email address specified at the bottom of the newsletter You receive. 

_Advertising_

We may send You email communications including information that We may think may be of interest to You. You may opt out of receiving these email communications either when You register to become a Member, via the Preferences section of XPlace, or by sending a message to the unsubscribe email address specified at the bottom of the newsletter You receive. We do not send any of your personal information to our advertisers. You may see a cookie from a third-party banner server, and this cookie comes from the third-party banner server, not XPlace. Again, we do not pass along any personal information to this party. 

_Co-Branded Services_

XPlace enters into co-branding relationships with third-party web sites and companies to provide products and services to our Users. XPlace may share your personal information, including User ID and password, with certain co-branded third-party service or product providers as required to provide a specific product or service that You request from a co-branded page or co-branded site. However, these third-party partners may not use this personal information for any reason other than to provide the service or product that the user has explicitly signed up for. 

If You join XPlace through a co-branded site (e.g., on a co-branded registration page), it is XPlace's general policy not to share anything other than summarized or aggregated data with the partner; however, any personal information You provide may also be received by the co-branded site and could be stored and used by the co-branded service or product provider according to their privacy policy. Please take the time to review these third-party privacy policies. 

_Service Providers and Project Owners_

Projects on XPlace are completed by experts registered with XPlace once a project is awarded. XPlace shares full contact information between the project owners and the expert selected for the project to enable work on the project to commence. The information shared includes name, company name, phone number, email and mailing address. In bidding on a project and/or accepting a expert's bid, you provide express permission and authority for XPlace to release your complete contact information to the other party involved in the transaction. XPlace is not liable for any misuse of your contact information by the party to which such information is released or by any other party, user or non-user. Please note that you may be held legally responsible for misusing contact information provided to you. 

_Legal Requests_

XPlace cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws, such as: intellectual property rights, fraud, theft, harassment and other rights. We can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose us or you to legal liability. Additionally, XPlace reserves the right (and you authorize XPlace) to communicate any information about you (including, but not limited to your policy violations, transactions and contact information) to other users and law enforcement as we in our sole discretion determine necessary or appropriate to maintain a level of trust and safety in our community and to enforce our Terms and Conditions of Use, Privacy Policy and any posted policies or rules applicable to services you use through our site. 

_Comments Submitted by Users_

XPlace constantly seeks to improve the quality of the services We provide and the User experience on the Site. We value your input and encourage You to help us expand and make improvements to the Site by providing Us with any thoughts or comments You might have regarding our services or the operation of the Site. You can submit any comments You have to Us by clicking on the link entitled "Contact Us" at the top of most of the pages on the Site. The "Contact Us" page asks for your name, email address and User ID. If You provide this information, we will only use it to acknowledge or respond to your comments. Submitting comments via an email will not cause you to receive any secondary or promotional material, unless specifically requested by You. In certain circumstances, we may ask for your permission to post your comments in marketing or promotional materials. 

## Security

XPlace is committed to providing You with a safe and secure e-commerce environment. We will use commercially reasonable methods to keep personal information securely in our files and systems. Please note that with current technology, we cannot guarantee the security of your data as it travels over the Internet. 

## Terminating Your Membership

If You terminate your membership, You may continue to receive email communications for a short period of time until we have updated all of our databases. After termination of your membership, your personal information may remain in our archives, databases and records for technical and auditing purposes. To discontinue your membership with XPlace, contact us by email at support [at] XPlace.com. 

## Your Info on Search Engines

You hereby acknowledge and confirm that XPlace permits search engines such as Google and Bing to index and reproduce your profile and related information in full or in part including your texts, your projects, your bids, your articles, and more, and you hereby agree in full and without any objection or limitation that 3rd party services, engines, bots, spiders and indexers will copy your information from XPlace. 

Furthermore, you hereby acknowledge and confirm that your information may appear on external search engines **even after you close your XPlace account** and that it is your sole responsibility to contact those companies, services, sites or search engines yourself with any requests for changes or removals of your data since XPlace is not responsible and does not have access to any data stored by 3rd party sites and search engines. Finally, you hereby acknowledge and confirm that **XPlace shall in no way be responsible for data or information that may appear on other sites or search engines**. 

## Correcting/Updating Your Information and Opting Out

This Site gives the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. You may update your registration information using the Options page, in the XPlace upper navigation bar after You register. This Site provides users the opportunity to opt out of receiving promotional email communications from us, XPlace newsletters and other site information using Preferences. 

## Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our website. 

CONTACTING US 

If you wish to report a violation of the Terms of Service, have any questions or need assistance, please contact XPlace Customer Support as follows: 

**Email:** support@xplace.com
